Norman Vincent Peale Papers
Norman Vincent Peale Papers
- II. Subject files
  - J: Testimonial Dinner
    - 20th Anniversary, Nov 18 1952 (Box II:J:4)
  - K: Guideposts
    Guideposts, a widely read inspirational magazine of which Dr. Peale was Editor-in-Chief, is subscribed to by hundreds of thousands of individuals as well as by many firms for their employees. Founders of Guideposts included Lowell Thomas, Capt. Eddie Rickenbacker, Branch Rickey, Walter Teagle, and Stanley Kresge. This subseries includes correspondence, manuscripts, printed and published materials, photographs, and newspaper clippings pertaining to Guideposts. Among the correspondents are such well known names as Lowell Thomas, Dale Carnegie, Henry J. Kaiser, Stanley Kresge, George E. Sokolsky, and Fulton Oursler. The material is arranged chronologically for the years 1944-1946 and 1945-1951, then alphabetically by subject or correspondent within these two year groups.
    - [General], 1944-1946
      - A (Box II:K:1)
      - Articles, not used (Box II:K:1)
      - Authors' Letters (Box II:K:1)
      - Authors, Prospective (Box II:K:1)
      - Authors' Suggestions (Box II:K:1)
      - B (Box II:K:1)
      - Bainbridge, William S (Box II:K:1)
      - Benson, Philip A (Box II:K:1)
      - Blanton, Dr. Smiley (Box II:K:1)
      - Bonnell, J.S. (Box II:K:1)
      - Boyer (Box II:K:1)
      - Bradley, J. Chapman (Box II:K:1)
      - C (Box II:K:1)
      - Carnegie, Dale (Box II:K:1)
      - Chamberlaine (Box II:K:1)
      - Clergymen (Box II:K:1)
      - Contributors Letters (Box II:K:1)
      - Crissey, A. Elwell (Box II:K:1)
      - D (Box II:K:1)
      - Detroit (Box II:K:2)
      - De Servensky (Box II:K:2)
      - E (Box II:K:2)
      - Engle (Box II:K:2)
      - Editorial, Atomic Bomb (Box II:K:2)
      - Editorial Suggestions (Box II:K:2)
      - F (Box II:K:2)
      - Filmore, Charles (Box II:K:2)
      - Ford, Henry (Box II:K:2)
      - Form Letters (Box II:K:2)
      - Forman, Henry J. (Box II:K:2)
      - G (Box II:K:2)
      - Guideposts articles, 1st Issue (Box II:K:2)
      - Guideposts articles, 2nd Issue (Box II:K:2)
      - Board (Box II:K:2)
      - Final Draft, 3rd Issue (Box II:K:2)
      - Final Draft, 4th Issue (Box II:K:2)
      - Final Draft, 5th-12th Issues (Box II:K:3)
      - Suggestions (Box II:K:3)
      - H (Box II:K:3)
      - Harris (Box II:K:4)
      - Hays, Brooks (Box II:K:4)
      - Hearst, Publicity (Box II:K:4)
      - Heckman, H.G. (Box II:K:4)
      - Howard, Stephanie (Box II:K:4)
      - Hoyden, Perry (Box II:K:4)
      - I (Box II:K:4)
      - Inquiries (Box II:K:4)
      - J (Box II:K:4)
      - Jaynes, Oliver (Box II:K:4)
      - K (Box II:K:4)
      - Kaiser, Harry J. (Box II:K:4)
      - Kiefer, Dixie (Box II:K:4)
      - Kresge, Stanley (Box II:K:4)
      - Letourneau, Robert G. (Box II:K:4)
      - Letter to Subscribers (Box II:K:4)
      - M (Box II:K:4)
      - Maish, Jay H Co. (Box II:K:4)
      - Malmberg, A.O. (Box II:K:4)
      - Mann, Stella (Box II:K:4)
      - Manuscripts (Box II:K:4)
      - McC (Box II:K:4)
      - McShane, Mary (Box II:K:4)
      - Merritt, Arthur H., D.D.S. (Box II:K:4)
      - Millinery Styles (Box II:K:5)
      - Mills, Ohio (Box II:K:5)
      - N (Box II:K:5)
      - O (Box II:K:5)
      - Originals (Box II:K:5)
      - Oursler, Fulton (Box II:K:5)
      - Overend articles (Box II:K:5)
      - P (Box II:K:5)
      - Palmer, Clyde (Box II:K:5)
      - "Pan" Mail (Box II:K:5)
      - Patterson, Grover (Box II:K:5)
      - Peale (Box II:K:5)
      - Peale, Manuscripts (Box II:K:5)
      - Peale, Notes (Box II:K:5)
      - Peale, personal (Box II:K:5)
      - Peale, Ruth (Box II:K:5)
      - Penney, J.C. (Box II:K:5)
      - Photographs (Box II:K:5)
      - Plummer, John T. (Box II:K:5)
      - Plummer articles (Box II:K:5)
      - Possible Material (Box II:K:6)
      - Publicity (Box II:K:6)
      - Pulvermacher, Joseph (Box II:K:6)
      - Q (Box II:K:6)
      - R (Box II:K:6)
      - Radcliff (Box II:K:6)
      - Radio and Theater News (Box II:K:6)
      - Rogue's Gallery (Box II:K:6)
      - Rumely, Edward A. (Box II:K:6)
      - S (Box II:K:6)
      - Sanders, Jessie (Box II:K:7)
      - Selby, H.W. (Box II:K:7)
      - Sokalsky, Barton (Box II:K:7)
      - Standard Coated Products (Box II:K:7)
      - T (Box II:K:7)
      - Television (Box II:K:7)
      - Thomas, Lowell (Box II:K:7)
      - Thornbury (Box II:K:7)
      - U (Box II:K:7)
      - V (Box II:K:7)
      - W (Box II:K:7)
      - Williamson, notes from (Box II:K:7)
      - Wright, Richardson (Box II:K:7)
      - X (Box II:K:7)
      - Y (Box II:K:7)
      - Z (Box II:K:7)
    - [General], 1945-1951
      - A (Box II:K:8)
      - Addresses (Box II:K:8)
      - Authors, Suggested I, II, III (Box II:K:8)
      - B (Box II:K:8)
      - Babson, Roger (Box II:K:9)
      - Barber, "Red" (Box II:K:9)
      - Bell, Jones and Taylor (Box II:K:9)
      - Bible Quiz (Box II:K:9)
      - Birch, Frank H. (Box II:K:9)
      - Bucke, Emory Stevens (Box II:K:9)
      - C (Box II:K:9)
      - Danforth, William H. (Box II:K:9)
      - Davis, Alice Elizabeth (Box II:K:10)
      - Decker, Frederick C. (Box II:K:10)
      - DeMille, Cecil B. (Box II:K:10)
      - Dodds, Gil (Box II:K:10)
      - E (Box II:K:10)
      - Editorial Board (Box II:K:10)
      - F (Box II:K:10)
      - Form Letters (Box II:K:10)
      - G (Box II:K:10)
      - Glossinger, John (Box II:K:11)
      - Granville, Irving (Box II:K:11)
      - Guideposts
        - Advisory Board (Box II:K:11)
        - Articles by Peale (Box II:K:11)
        - Book (Box II:K:11)
        - Daily Report (Box II:K:11)
        - Foundation (Box II:K:12)
        - Luncheon (Box II:K:12)
        - [Miscellaneous], January-June 1948 (Box II:K:12)
        - Miscellaneous matter (Box II:K:12)
        - Reports (Box II:K:13)
        - Syndication (Box II:K:13)
      - H (Box II:K:13)
      - Hake, Alfred P. (Box II:K:13)
      - Hayes, Roland (Box II:K:13)
      - Hoover (Box II:K:13)
      - I (Box II:K:13)
      - J (Box II:K:13)
      - K (Box II:K:14)
      - Kessel, Bert (Box II:K:14)
      - LeSourd, Leonard (Box II:K:14)
      - M (Box II:K:14)
      - Marish, Jay H. Co. (Box II:K:15)
      - Malmberg, A.O. (Box II:K:15)
      - Mc (Box II:K:15)
      - Moulton, Ruth (Box II:K:15)
      - N (Box II:K:15)
      - O (Box II:K:15)
      - Oursler, Ruth (Box II:K:15)
      - P (Box II:K:15)
      - Peale, Norman V. (Box II:K:16)
      - Peale, articles not used (Box II:K:16)
      - Penn, Henry (Box II:K:16)
      - Pictures (Box II:K:16)
      - Q (Box II:K:16)
      - R (Box II:K:16)
      - Release Forms (Box II:K:16)
      - Rondeau, Noah John (Box II:K:16)
      - Russell, Harold (Box II:K:16)
      - S (Box II:K:16)
      - Sheppard, Russell (Box II:K:17)
      - Singing Sam - Sammy Cascavilla (Box II:K:17)
      - Smith, Maurice C. Jr (Box II:K:17)
      - Stidger, William L. (Box II:K:17)
      - Stoll, George (Box II:K:17)
      - T (Box II:K:17)
      - Taylor, Henry J. (Box II:K:17)
      - Thompson, Edward (Box II:K:17)
      - Thornburg, Raymond (Box II:K:17)
      - U (Box II:K:17)
      - V (Box II:K:17)
      - W (Box II:K:17)
      - XYZ (Box II:K:17)
      - Young, Ralston (Box II:K:17)
  - L: Sermon Publications
    Sermon Publications (also containing Foundation for Christian Living materials) of Pawling, New York, publishes and distributes Dr. Peale's sermons and inspirational literature. These are sent to thousands each month. This subseries contains organizational records pertaining to the Foundation and published material. There is also correspondence from people requesting publications or commenting on them. This subseries is arranged chronologically and then alphabetically within the year.
    - Sermon Publication Reports, 1946-1947 (Box II:L:1)
    - Guideposts, 1948 (Box II:L:1)
    - Receipts, 1948 (Box II:L:1)
    - Projects and Promotion Records, 1949-1951 (Box II:L:1)
    - Dutcher House, 1950 (Box II:L:1)
    - Office Supplies, 1952 (Box II:L:1)
    - Peale, Mrs. Norman V., 1952 (Box II:L:1)
    - Sermon Publications, 1952 (Box II:L:1)
    - Sermon Publications Correspondence, 1952 (Box II:L:2)
    - [General], 1953
      - Bookkeeping (Box II:L:2)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:3)
      - Open House Material (Box II:L:3)
      - Peale, Dr. and Mrs. (Box II:L:3)
      - Promotion (Box II:L:3)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:3)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:4)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:5)
    - [General], 1954
      - Bookkeeping (Box II:L:5)
      - Department of Labor (Box II:L:5)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:5)
      - McCall's magazine (Box II:L:5)
      - Old Sermon Lists (Box II:L:6)
      - Projects and Promotions (Box II:L:6)
      - Sermon Index (Box II:L:6)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:6)
    - [General], 1955
      - Accounts Receivable (Box II:L:6)
      - Bookkeeping (Box II:L:6)
      - Credits and Debts (Box II:L:6)
      - Elliott (Box II:L:7)
      - Government Forms (Box II:L:7)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:7)
      - Hooven Letters, Inc. (Box II:L:7)
      - Look-Post Hall (Box II:L:7)
      - Manuscripts, Proofs, NBC (Box II:L:7)
      - Peale, Dr. and Mrs. Norman V. (Box II:L:7)
      - Postage Rates, Etc. (Box II:L:7)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:8)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:9)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:10)
    - [General], 1956
      - Accounts Payable (Box II:L:10)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:11)
      - I.B.M. Equipment (Box II:L:11)
      - Misc. quotations (Box II:L:11)
      - Pawling (Box II:L:11)
      - Petty Cash Promotions (Box II:L:11)
      - Special Staff (Box II:L:11)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:11)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:12)
    - [General], 1957
      - Church Calendars (Box II:L:13)
      - Discontinued Mailings (Box II:L:13)
      - G (Box II:L:13)
      - Guideposts advertising (Box II:L:13)
      - Guideposts letters (Box II:L:13)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:13)
      - H (Box II:L:13)
      - I (Box II:L:13)
      - Income, Misc. (Box II:L:13)
      - Income, Petty Cash (Box II:L:14)
      - Industrial Prospects (Box II:L:14)
      - J (Box II:L:14)
      - K (Box II:L:14)
      - L (Box II:L:14)
      - Look Reports (Box II:L:14)
      - Loomis, Payson (Box II:L:14)
      - M (Box II:L:14)
      - N (Box II:L:14)
      - O (Box II:L:14)
      - P (Box II:L:14)
      - Pending (Box II:L:15)
      - Printing (Box II:L:15)
      - R-S (Box II:L:15)
      - Salescience, Bank Records (Box II:L:15)
      - Salescience I.C.R. (Box II:L:15)
      - Schools, Requests, Sacramento CA, State Superintendant (Box II:L:15)
      - T (Box II:L:16)
      - Teenage Booklets (Box II:L:16)
      - V-W (Box II:L:16)
      - Vacations (Box II:L:16)
      - Van Werlin, Mrs. - Books (Box II:L:16)
      - X-Y-Z (Box II:L:16)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:16)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:17)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:18)
    - [General], 1958
      - Blue Cross (Box II:L:19)
      - Bulk, New (Box II:L:19)
      - Bulk, Replies (Box II:L:19)
      - Firms (Box II:L:19)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:19)
      - H-L (Box II:L:20)
      - Large Requests, A-T (Box II:L:20)
      - Large Requests, U-Z (Box II:L:21)
      - Large Requests, Churches (Box II:L:21)
      - Look (Box II:L:21)
      - Look Reports (Box II:L:21)
      - Loomis, Payson (Box II:L:21)
      - M (Box II:L:21)
      - Marble Collegiate Church (Box II:L:22)
      - Mc-P (Box II:L:22)
      - Promotion Forms (Box II:L:22)
      - Q-R (Box II:L:22)
      - Reports (Box II:L:22)
      - S-T (Box II:L:23)
      - Testimonial Copies (Box II:L:23)
      - Tops (Box II:L:23)
      - U-Wh (Box II:L:23)
      - Wi-Z (Box II:L:24)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:24)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:25)
    - [General], 1959
      - A-B (Box II:L:25)
      - Baptist (Box II:L:25)
      - Bookkeeping (Box II:L:25)
      - Bulk: New, Replies (Box II:L:26)
      - C (Box II:L:26)
      - Chapel (Box II:L:26)
      - Christmas Cards (Box II:L:26)
      - D-F (Box II:L:26)
      - Firms, Replies (Box II:L:26)
      - G (Box II:L:27)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:27)
      - H (Box II:L:27)
      - I-K (Box II:L:27)
      - Invoices (Box II:L:27)
      - L (Box II:L:27)
      - Letters from New Book (Box II:L:28)
      - M-P (Box II:L:28)
      - Promotion Forms (Box II:L:28)
      - Q-R (Box II:L:28)
      - Radio (Box II:L:28)
      - Radio (Box II:L:29)
      - S-Z (Box II:L:29)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:29)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence (Box II:L:30)
    - [General], 1960
      - A-Baz (Box II:L:30)
      - Baptist (Box II:L:31)
      - Be-D (Box II:L:31)
      - E-G (Box II:L:32)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:32)
      - H-K (Box II:L:33)
      - L-M (Box II:L:34)
      - N-P (Box II:L:35)
      - Presbyterian (Box II:L:35)
      - Promotion Forms (Box II:L:35)
      - Q-R (Box II:L:35)
      - S-T (Box II:L:36)
      - Tour Information (Box II:L:36)
      - Tour Replies (Box II:L:36)
      - U-V (Box II:L:36)
      - W-Z (Box II:L:37)
      - File #2, A (Box II:L:37)
      - Argue, Thomas F. (Box II:L:37)
      - Attendance Records (Box II:L:37)
      - B-Cl (Box II:L:37)
      - Church Statements (Box II:L:37)
      - Co-Cv (Box II:L:38)
      - Correspondence Peale (Box II:L:38)
      - D-De (Box II:L:38)
      - Dart, Justin (Box II:L:38)
      - Di-F (Box II:L:39)
      - Finances - National Bank (Box II:L:39)
      - Finances, F.C.L. (Box II:L:40)
      - Finances, Reports (Box II:L:40)
      - Form Letters (Box II:L:40)
      - G (Box II:L:40)
      - Good Letters (Box II:L:40)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:40)
      - H-I (Box II:L:40)
      - Industrials (Box II:L:40)
      - Inspirational Book Service (Box II:L:40)
      - Insurance (Box II:L:41)
      - Intercom Directives (Box II:L:41)
      - J-L (Box II:L:41)
      - Letters (Box II:L:41)
      - M (Box II:L:41)
      - Memos (Box II:L:41)
      - Misc. Income (Box II:L:41)
      - Mc-O (Box II:L:41)
      - P (Box II:L:42)
      - Peale, Dr. R.C. (Box II:L:42)
      - Peale, Mrs. C.C., personal (Box II:L:42)
      - Petty Cash (Box II:L:42)
      - Pledges (Box II:L:42)
      - R (Box II:L:42)
      - Radio (Box II:L:43)
      - Sa-Sh (Box II:L:43)
      - Second Thoughts (Box II:L:43)
      - Si-T (Box II:L:43)
      - Tour (Box II:L:43)
      - Tour Accounts (Box II:L:43)
      - Tour, Inspirational (Box II:L:43)
      - Tour, NY (Box II:L:44)
      - Tour Transfers (Box II:L:44)
      - U-Z (Box II:L:44)
    - [General], 1961
      - A-Baz (Box II:L:44)
      - Baptist (Box II:L:44)
      - Bible Tributes (Box II:L:44)
      - Be-Bri (Box II:L:44)
      - Bro-C (Box II:L:45)
      - Correspondence Peale, Dr. (Box II:L:45)
      - D-Gl (Box II:L:45)
      - Gifts - Responses (Box II:L:45)
      - Go-Gz (Box II:L:45)
      - Guideposts (Box II:L:45)
      - H (Box II:L:46)
      - How to Be Young (Box II:L:46)
      - I (Box II:L:46)
      - I.B.S. (Box II:L:46)
      - J-Li (Box II:L:46)
      - Loomis, Payson (Box II:L:46)
      - Lutheran (Box II:L:46)
      - Mc-Az (Box II:L:46)
      - McChurch (Box II:L:46)
      - Maa-Maz (Box II:L:46)
      - Marble Collegiate Church (Box II:L:46)
      - Me-Mi (Box II:L:47)
      - Methodist (Box II:L:47)
      - Mm-Pi (Box II:L:47)
      - Peale, Norman and Ruth (Box II:L:47)
      - Peale (Box II:L:47)
      - Pm-Pz (Box II:L:47)
      - Presbyterian (Box II:L:47)
      - Q-T (Box II:L:47)
      - Tour, NY (Box II:L:47)
      - Tour, NY - LeSourd (Box II:L:47)
      - UV (Box II:L:47)
      - Wa-Z (Box II:L:48)
      - Sermon Publication Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box II:L:48)
    - [General], 1963
      - A-Cb (Box II:L:48)
      - Ch-Kl (Box II:L:49)
      - L-T (Box II:L:50)
      - T-Z (Box II:L:51)
      - A-Ce (Box II:L:51)
      - Ch-Ha (Box II:L:52)
      - He-M (Box II:L:53)
      - N-Tl (Box II:L:54)
      - Tm-Z (Box II:L:55)
- III. Manuscripts
  Manuscripts is divided into two parts: A) Manuscripts by Dr. Peale, and B) Manuscripts by Others.
  - A: Manuscripts by Peale
    This subseries includes manuscripts of addresses, articles, books, book chapters, columns, and pamphlets. Addresses, articles, and columns are arranged alphabetically by type, then chronologically. Books, book chapters and pamphlets are arranged alphabetically by type, then alphabetically by title.
    - Addresses
      - No title, 1937 (Box III:1)
      - Preaching in 1942, 1942 (Box III:1)
      - The Right to Work, 1942 (Box III:1)
      - No title, Undated (Box III:1)
    - Articles
      - Articles, 1941 (Box III:1)
      - Articles, 1947-1948 (Box III:1)
      - Articles, 1949; Coronet Magazine, Edison Birthday (Box III:1)
      - Articles, 1950-1951 (Box III:1)
      - Articles, 1960-1961; undated; "Use the Great Powers in Your Mind" (Box III:2)
    - Blueprints for Pawling, NY Church
    - Books
      - Courage to Live, 1942; Chapters I-IX (Box III:2)
      - A Guide to Confident Living, undated; Chapters I-X (Box III:3)
      - How to Be Happy and Successful, 1947; Chapters I-VIII (Box III:3)
      - Live Forever, 1956 (Box III:4)
      - Live With Yourself and Like It, 1940-1944; undated; Chapters I-X, misc. material (Box III:4)
      - [New book]
        - Original manuscript, 1949 (Box III:5)
        - Chapters, 1955 (Box III:5)
        - Chapters, 1956 (Box III:6)
        - Correspondence and research material, 1949 (Box III:6)
        - Proposed outline (Box III:7)
        - Research material, 1952-1956 (Box III:7)
      - Power of Positive Thinking, undated; Chapters I-XIV; galley proof (Box III:7)
      - [No title], Chapters I-VIII (Box III:8)
      - [Unidentified book chapters]
        - "Don't Be Depressed - Get Your Spirits Lifted" (Box III:8)
        - "Relax and Live Efficiently, How to Really Stop Worrying" (Box III:8)
    - Columns, 1943 (Box III:8)
    - Pamphlets
      - Live Longer and Better, 1958 (Box III:8)
      - What to Do When, 1956 (Box III:9)
      - Your Key to Self Confidence, 1955 (Box III:9)
  - B: Manuscripts by others
    This subseries includes manuscripts for an anthology, A Treasury of Inspiration, by Helen and Horace Johnson, a book And Ensure the Blessings of Liberty, by Felix Morley, and an article by Sarah Schofield, entitled "Why I go to Church". This material is arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Johnson, Helen and Horace, Anthology / A Treasury of Inspiration (Box III:9)
    - Morley, Felix, Book / And Ensure the Blessings of Liberty (Box III:9)
    - Schofield, Sarah Wheeler, Article "Why I Go to Church" (Box III:9)
- IV. Personal file
  Personal file is divided into two parts: A) General file and B) Published material.
  - A: General file
    This subseries includes Dr. Peale's personal correspondence with his parents, wife and friends. Also, there are diaries, notes, clippings, and publicity material. There is also correspondence relating to his acceptance of the pastorate of the Marble Collegiate Church. This material is arranged alphabetically by subject or type.
    - After Dinner Stories (Box IV:1)
    - Bills, 1933-1936 (Box IV:1)
    - Calendars, 1957 (Box IV:1)
    - Certificates, Receipts and Statements (Box IV:1)
    - Certificates, Tickets, Passports, etc. (Box IV:1)
    - Clippings on C.C. Peale's Retirement (Box IV:1)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1924; 1926-1927 (Box IV:1)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1933 (Box IV:2)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1936; undated (Box IV:3)
    - Diaries, 1921; 1928-1930 (Box IV:3)
    - Drawings by Kallen, Morris, 1953 (Box IV:3)
    - Essays, 1921-1923 (Box IV:3)
    - Essays, 1923-1924 (Box IV:4)
    - History of Kings Highway M.E. Church, undated (Box IV:4)
    - Lenses (Box IV:4)
    - Lenten Talks (Box IV:4)
    - License, 1921 (Box IV:4)
    - Map (Box IV:4)
    - Memorandums, 1956 (Box IV:4)
    - Notes from Boston University, 1921-1922 (Box IV:4)
    - Notes from Boston University, 1922-1924 (Box IV:5)
    - Notes on Psychology of Religion by Strickland, 1923 (Box IV:5)
    - Photographs (Box IV:6)
    - Photographs
    - Photographs and Drawings of Beechcraft Airplanes (Box IV:7)
    - Poems (Box IV:7)
    - Publicity Material, 1949; 1951
    - Record Books, 1922; 1925-1926 (Box IV:8)
    - Resolution, 1942 (Box IV:8)
    - Scrapbooks, 1922; 1933-1935,; 1955 (Box IV:8)
    - Thesis, 1921 (Box IV:9)
    - Unpublished book, The Moriartys, 1957 (Box IV:9)
  - B: Published material
    This subseries contains an address by Wendell Willkie, articles by and about Dr. Peale, book reviews, newspaper clippings about Dr. Peale and pamphlets written by him. The material is arranged alphabetically by type, then alphabetically by title with the exception of articles about Dr. Peale, which are arranged chronologically.
    - Address by Willkie, Wendell L., 1935 (Box IV:9)
    - Annual Reports, 1921-1936 (Box IV:9)
    - Ohio M.E. Church, 1933 (Box IV:9)
    - Onondaga Orphans Home, 1929-1930 (Box IV:9)
    - Articles by Peale, A-H, 1938-1954 (Box IV:9)
    - Articles by Peale, I-Z, 1949-1955 (Box IV:10)
    - The Ministry of Today (Box IV:10)
    - Untitled, 1926; 1944 (Box IV:10)
    - Articles About Peale, 1927-1938; 1941-1951,; 1953-1955 (Box IV:10)
    - Book Reviews
      - New York Herald Tribune, 1953 (Box IV:10)
      - New York Times, 1950; 1953 (Box IV:10)
    - Bulletins
      - Ohio Wesleyan University, 1920-1928 (Box IV:11)
      - Syracuse University, 1930-1932 (Box IV:11)
    - Directory, 1923-1924 (Box IV:11)
    - Minutes, the Gen. Synod of the Reformed Church in America, 1932-1933 (Box IV:11)
    - Newspaper clippings by Peale (Box IV:11)
    - Newspaper clippings about Peale (Box IV:12)
    - Newspaper clippings about Peale (Box IV:13)
    - Newspaper clippings about Peale (Box IV:14)
    - Pamphlets by Peale, 1944 (Box IV:14)
    - Pamphlets by others, A-N, 1905-1938 (Box IV:14)
    - Pamphlets by Others, P-Z, 1895-1931 (Box IV:15)
    - Periodicals
      - Bell Telephone Quarterly, 1938 (Box IV:15)
      - The New York Woman, 1936
    - Programs
      - Duke University (Box IV:15)
      - First Methodist Episcopal Church (Box IV:15)
      - Kings Highway M.E. Church (Box IV:15)
      - Marble Collegiate M.E. Church (Box IV:16)
      - Mount Lebanon M.E. Church (Box IV:16)
      - Ohio Wesleyan University (Box IV:16)
      - Rotary International - 40th Annual Convention, 1949 (Box IV:16)
      - University M.E. Church (Box IV:16)
      - Westwood Methodist Episcopal Church (Box IV:16)
    - Standing Rules of Minister Etc. of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church, NY, 1921; 1932 (Box IV:16)
    - Yearbooks, C-K, 1925-1935 (Box IV:16)